Contact

christian.templeton@gmail.c

www.linkedin.com/in/ctempleton (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Program Management
Cross-functional Team Leadership
Strategy

Languages

Spanish Italian

Certifications

SQL Essential Training
Foundations of Programming:
Fundamentals

Christian Templeton

Finance Modernization

San Francisco Bay Area

Summary

I've held a variety of strategic roles within finance and controllership organizations in tech. With one foot planted in finance, I've spent my career pivoting between go-to-market and engineering organizations to drive cross-functional change. I joined Google from Salesforce to do this on a bigger scale, where I now lead initiatives spanning multiple years, product areas and geographies.

My speciality is modernizing finance organizations by driving transformation across:

- ✓ Go-to-market (GTM): Order to cash transformation, sales expansion, localization
- ✓ Deal teams: Deal desk, M&A, divestiture, ventures, tender offer, entity structuring
- ✓ Strategic finance: FP&A, long-range planning, product & program management
- ✓ Controllership: Complex revenue, SOX, statutory, external & segment reporting

Mission-driven organizations I've supported are driving advancements in areas such as health & wellness and education through data & analytics and machine learning.

Experience

Google

Finance Systems & Transformation April 2015 - Present (8 years 5 months)

Senior Manager, Finance Solutions & Transformation

- Co-lead order to cash transformation spanning multiple years, product areas and geographies to deliver against investment in system and process automation

- Guide growth companies and Bets through monetization and system independence
- Fundraise for vulnerable communities, crowdfunding across networks at Google (e.g. Google.org, disability alliance, barbell club, mountain biking) and other tech peers
- Form and participate in industry roundtables to share and learn from best practices
- Oversee return-to-office, hybrid workweek and team culture projects and objectives

Manager, Finance Solutions & Transformation

- Rollout multi-year, multi-country adoption of local selling and other strategic tax initiatives
- Deploy in-country discovery teams to reduce requirements phase by multiple months
- Scale teams' operational activities through automation (ML, SQL & Apps Script)
- Improve spend transparency via audit committee report-outs and monthly newsletter

Manager, Strategy, Systems & Integration

- Propose to Chief Accounting Officer acceleration to cash flow reporting, mapping data source by team
- Establish reporting dashboard to track Google-wide new product launches, a top worldwide finance highlight
- Publish monthly Operational Excellence dashboard for Finance VP leading up to earnings, with metrics spanning full P&L, balance sheet and cash conversion cycle
- Design and deliver SQL training to finance, legal and corporate engineering -- used in advanced SQL course rolled out to worldwide finance

Salesforce

Finance & Strategy Operations
January 2014 - April 2015 (1 year 4 months)

Manager, Finance & Strategy Operations

- Lead Metrics Revolution, elevating SaaS metrics to VPs in finance, accounting and sales to improve sales productivity, leading to lower cost to book and customer churn

- Business Product Owner for internal finance use case of Analytics Cloud, managing senior business analyst and forming scrum team to launch 10 sales and marketing datasets through ETLT
- Align finance and engineering through requirements gathering, kick-off, daily scrums, sprint planning, review and retrospectives
- Develop, implement and administer excel case interviews within finance to change how finance candidates are assessed against analytics capabilities

Symantec

Corporate FP&A

March 2011 - December 2013 (2 years 10 months)

Manager, Performance Analysis

- Develop deal desk for strategic partnerships such as enabling Symantec to become official Rio Olympics supplier, modeling deal economics for sales and marketing
- Design and implement frameworks for activity-based costing, product profitability by revenue type and tracking of go-to-market initiatives sponsored by office of the CEO

Manager, M&A

- Lead cross-functional finance team of 20 and target company management through due diligence, on-site discovery, valuation, close and integration
- Drive disentanglement planning and contribute to divestiture playbook and best practices

Principal Financial Analyst, Corporate FP&A

 Publish product profitability analysis informing opportunities for growth or divestiture of > 30 business units, used by new CEO and organizational design consultants

Senior Financial Specialist, Corporate FP&A

- Lead zero-based budget, forecast, plan and quarter close, providing material to CFO, board of directors, audit committee, investor relations/analysts and external auditors

Seagate Technology
Corporate Finance
March 2008 - March 2011 (3 years 1 month)
Senior Accountant, SOX PMO

- Appointed by CFO to collaborate with cross-functional stakeholder groups on Information Protection Strategy committee

SOX Analyst

- Use Kepner-Tregoe (KT) decision model to select new SOX 404 system, lead user acceptance testing, and implement application to reduce latency and total cost of ownership

External Reporting/SOX Intern

- Audit leases and develop straight-line model to streamline lease expense recording
- Prepare and file statutory reporting with revenue, expense and headcount by location

Education

Santa Clara University - Leavey School of Business MBA, Accounting Concentration

University of California, Santa Cruz Bachelor's degree, Modern Literature

The Data Incubator
Data Science